A Finding Aid to the Linda Nochlin Papers, circa 1876, 1937-2017, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Teaching Files, 1953-2012; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 2.5 Linear feet Boxes 23-25, OV 36; 0.016 Gigabytes ER104-ER119
  - Courses, 1953-2012; 6.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Manet and His Critics, 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Manet and His Critics, 2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Manet Seminar, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - Manet Seminar, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - The Modern Portrait Seminar, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - Monet, Cézanne and the Modern Imagination Seminar, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 42)
    - Museums Class, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 24, Folder 43)
    - Neoclassicism, 1969-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Neofeminism, 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Neo-impressionism and Seurat Seminar, 1993-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Paris in the 19th Century Seminar, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Phantasmagorias of Modernity in 19th Century France: Fetishism and the Feminine in Art and Literature Seminar, 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Post-Impressionism, 1985-1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Post-Impressionism, 1993-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Post-Impressionism, 1994-1996; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 21 computer files (Folder ER115)
    - Post-Impressionism, 1997-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Post-Impressionism, 2000; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 3 computer files (Folder ER116)
    - Post-Impressionism, Van Gogh in Arles Seminar, 1994-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - The Realist Imagination: Artists and Ideas in the 19th and 20th Century Seminar, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Reconstructing Realism: Courbet and His Critics, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Renoir and Feminism, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Renoir and His Critics Seminar, 2008; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - The Representation of Misère in the Art of the 19th Century, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - The Representation of Poverty and Misery Seminar, 2010-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Theater Seminar, 1996-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Theater Seminar, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 36)
    - Van Gogh Class, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Visual Significance and Urban Culture Seminar, 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Women and Art Seminar, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Women Artists Class: Dorothea Tanning, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Women Artists and Their Critics, 2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Women Artists and Their Critics, 2006; 2011-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Women Artists and Their Critics, 1997-2011; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 36)
  - Other Teaching Files, circa 1970-2012; 6.2; Archival Resource Key
    The material in this subseries includes bibliographies, student correspondence that includes a few student papers, library catalog lists, teaching assistant duties, a lease between Richard Pommer and Vassar College, and letters of recommendation written by Nochlin.
    - Bibliographies, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Digital Fragments of Various Teaching Materials, 1994-2000; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 4 computer files (Folder ER117)
    - Lease for Richard Pommer at Vassar College, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Letters of Recommendation by Nochlin, 1995-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Letters of Recommendation by Nochlin, 1991-2005; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 49 computer files (Folder ER118)
    - Library Catalog Lists, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Meeting Material Regarding Curriculum Requirements at IFA, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Pommer Course Material, Kahn and Architecture, 1991-1992; Archival Resource Key; 0.001 Gigabytes 5 computer files (Folder ER119)
    - Program for Art on Film, 1996-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Student Correspondence, 1971-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Student Correspondence, 1992-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Student Correspondence, 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Student Correspondence, 1998-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Student Correspondence Regarding Papers on Courbet, 1975-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Student Correspondence with Paper on Sally Mann, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Student Correspondence Regarding Duchamp, circa 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - Syllabi and Course Material at IFA, 1999-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Syllabi and Bibliographies at Yale University and IFA, 1990-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Teaching Assistant Duties, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 25, Folder 38)
- Printed Materials, 1939-2017; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 3 Linear feet Boxes 26-28, 32, 34, OVs 39-40
  A large portion of the series includes heavily annotated books used by Nochlin for research. Many of the booklets, clippings, exhibition catalogs, journals and magazines, newsletters, and offprints feature published writings by Nochlin or reviews of her work. Also included are broadcasts and documentary material on five video recordings, flyers, invitations, posters, and postcards collected and labeled "My Life in Postcards" by Nochlin.
  The series is arranged by format, then arranged chronologically.
  - Books, 1939; circa 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Books, 1956; 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Books, 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Books, 1963-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Books, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Books, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Books, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Books, 1971; 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Books, 1972; 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Books, 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Books, 1981-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Books, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Books, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Books, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Books, 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Books, 1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Books, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Books, 1990; 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Books, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Books, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Books, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Books, 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Book Jacket Covers, 1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Booklets, Published Writings by Nochlin, 2007-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Booklets/Pamphlets, 1974-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Broadcast, "Feminist Art History," American Art Forum, 1989; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Short Film Home by Sandy Perlbinder, 1989; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) Cassette label does not match contents of the video. (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Documentary, American Visions, Vols. 2-3, 1996; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Documentary, The Other Side of the Picture, 1999; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1970-2003; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 39)
  - Clippings, 1980s-2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 2000-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, Published Essays by Nochlin, 1967-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, Published Essays by Nochlin, 1967-1989; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, Published Essays by Nochlin, 1994-2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, Reviews of Nochlin Writings, 1972-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, Reviews of Nochlin Writings, 2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, Vassar College Publications on Nochlin, 1972-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1977; 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Exhibition Catalogs with Writings by Nochlin, 1968-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Exhibition Catalogs with Writings by Nochlin, 2001-2007; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Exhibition Catalog, Buy My Bananas, 2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition Catalog, Kiss Kiss Bang Bang: 45 Years of Art and Feminism, circa 2004; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition Catalog, The Order of Things, 2015; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Exhibition Catalog, Women Artists: 1550-1950 Excerpt, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1993-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Event Announcements, circa 2005; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Flyers, circa 1980-2011; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Invitations, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Journal, Rutgers Art Review, 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 17)
    Journal includes an interview with Nochlin.
  - Journals, 1974-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Journals, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Magazine, Senior Scholastic, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 19)
    The "Young Voices" section features writing by Nochlin.
  - Magazine, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Newsletters, 1976-2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Newsletters, Vassar Miscellany News, 1948-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Offprints of Nochlin's Writings, 1981-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Offprints, "Why Have There Been No Great Women Artists?", 2016-2017; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Offprints, Writings by Others, circa 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Postcards, Letters from Box 32, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Postcards, circa 1960-circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 32)
    Original box label read "My Life in Postcards."
  - Posters, 1975-2012; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 40)
- Artwork, circa 1940-2004; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Boxes 28, 34, OV 38
  Artwork by Nochlin includes sketches in ink, charcoal, paint, and pencil created from childhood into her early 20s as class or personal projects. Artwork by others includes a folder of painted sketches by children, possibly Nochlin's grandchildren, and one video recording of video art by Zoulikha Bouabdellah.
  The series is arranged by type of artwork, then arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Charcoal Sketch, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 38)
  - Ink Sketches and Prints, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 38)
  - Ink Sketches and Prints, circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Ink Sketch of Mary Queen of Scots, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Painted Sketches, circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Painted Sketches, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 38)
  - Painted Sketches by Children, 1988; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Pastel, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Pencil Sketches, circa 1940s; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 31)
  - Pencil and Paint Project, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 32)
  - Pencil and Pastel Sketches, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 33)
  - Pencil and Ink Sketches/Doodles, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 34)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Sketchbook, circa 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Sketchbook, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Video Art by Zoulikha Bouabdellah, 2000-2004; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 28, Folder 35)
- Photographic Materials, circa 1935-circa 2010; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Boxes 28-29, 34
  Photographic material is of Nochlin with artists Nancy Graves, Sebastian Horsley, and Shirley Jaffe; of Nochlin by Annie Appel, Mel Rosenthal, and Patrick McMullen; with family members including her children and husbands; group photographs of Nochlin's childhood school class and later in life at professional events; personal snapshots of friends and colleagues; students; snapshots of travel to France, Prague, Rome, and other locations; and works of art including Nochlin's piece "Achetez des Bananes." The photographs in the file for Nochlin and Richard Pommer's wedding depicts the couple in the same wedding attire shown in Portrait of Linda Nochlin & Richard Pommer by Philip Pearlstein.
  The series is roughly arranged by subject. Photographic material featuring Nochlin and her family appears earlier in the series, followed by events, friends and colleagues, group photos, students and colleagues, travel, Vassar College, and works of art. The material within the folders is also roughly arranged chronologically.
  - Nochlin, circa 1935-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 36)
  - Nochlin and Richard Pommer Wedding, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - Family, 1964-circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - Nochlin with Abigail Solomon-Godeau, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 39)
  - Nochlin by Annie Appel at Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 40)
  - Nochlin by Mel Rosenthal, 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 41)
  - Nochlin with Michael Shernoff, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 42)
  - Nochlin with Nancy Graves at Graves' Studio, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 43)
  - Nochlin at Opening of Women Artists: 1550-1950 Exhibition, 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 44)
  - Nochlin with Orange Disaster by Deborah Kass, circa 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 45)
  - Nochlin by Patrick McMullan, circa 2006; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 46)
  - Nochlin with Sebastian Horsley, 2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 47)
  - Nochlin with Shirley Jaffe, circa 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 48)
  - Nochlin at Vassar College, 1947-circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 49)
  - Event, Protest, circa 1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 50)
  - Events, Reception, 2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 51)
  - Friends, circa 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 52)
  - Friends, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 53)
  - Friends and Colleagues, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 54)
  - Friends and Colleagues, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 55)
  - Friends and Colleagues, circa 1980s; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 56)
  - Friends and Colleagues (1 of 2), circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Friends and Colleagues (2 of 2), circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Friends and Colleagues, circa 2000s; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Group Photos, circa 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Group Photos, circa 1940-2012; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Students and Colleagues, circa 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Travel, California and Santa Fe, N.M., circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Travel, France, circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Travel, France with Ewa Lajer-Burcharth, circa 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Travel, Hawaii, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Travel, Netherlands at Cube House, 1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Travel, Portland, O.R., 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Travel, Prague, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Travel, Rome, 1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 13)
    Includes a letter from Ewa Lajer-Burcharth.
  - Travel, Vancouver Island, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Vassar College, 1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Works of Art, "Achetez des Bananes" [Buy My Bananas], 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Works of Art, circa 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 17)